<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Shalhan Assalam - Data Analyst</title>
    <link>https://hansproject.github.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Shalhan Assalam - Data Analyst</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hansproject.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Samba Commerce Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://hansproject.github.io/projects/samba-commerce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hansproject.github.io/projects/samba-commerce/</guid>
      <description>Situation As data analyst in Samba Commerce, the CEO ask me to make dashboard to capture and understand more metrics and make the business data more comprehensive and insightful.
Backround You are a data analyst at one of the fast growing ecommerce in Brazil named Samba Commerce, which just launched in 2021. Samba Commerce offers more than 15k products, and more than 50 product categories to the customers all over Brazil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RevoBank Fintech Analysis | Part 1: EDA</title>
      <link>https://hansproject.github.io/projects/revobank-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hansproject.github.io/projects/revobank-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Situation This the first part of RevoBank analysis, focused on EDA and A/B testing analysis.
As a Data Analyst on RevoBank&amp;rsquo;s Card Partnerships team, I was tasked with evaluating and optimizing a 6-month promotional rewards program with RevoShop to increase credit card usage and revenue while reducing program costs. My role was to analyze customer data to provide insights into behaviors that could inform strategies for customizing the rewards by segment to boost engagement in a more cost-effective manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RevoBank Fintech Analysis | Part 2: Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://hansproject.github.io/projects/revobank-analysis2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hansproject.github.io/projects/revobank-analysis2/</guid>
      <description>Situation This the second part of RevoBank analysis, focused on segmentation analysis using RFM and K-means.
As a Data Analyst on RevoBank&amp;rsquo;s Card Partnerships team, I was tasked with evaluating and optimizing a 6-month promotional rewards program with RevoShop to increase credit card usage and revenue while reducing program costs. My role was to analyze customer data to provide insights into behaviors that could inform strategies for customizing the rewards by segment to boost engagement in a more cost-effective manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RevoBank Fintech Analysis | Part 3: Propensity Modelling</title>
      <link>https://hansproject.github.io/projects/revobank-analysis3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hansproject.github.io/projects/revobank-analysis3/</guid>
      <description>Situation This the last part of RevoBank analysis, we develop machine learning with propensity modelling using logit regression.
As a Data Analyst at RevoBank, I developed a propensity model to predict customers likely to adopt the new PayLater installment feature for a targeted promotion campaign.
Backround RevoBank launched a 3-month pilot for a PayLater installment feature on RevoShop transactions. The pilot demonstrated potential to increase credit card usage. To further boost activation, RevoBank proposed Project Contact - contacting customers to offer rewards for trying PayLater.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luxura Analysis Part 1</title>
      <link>https://hansproject.github.io/projects/luxura-analysis1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hansproject.github.io/projects/luxura-analysis1/</guid>
      <description>Situation In this project, I&amp;rsquo;m part of Luxura&amp;rsquo;s Data Analytics team. As fashion e-commerce company, Luxura selling several luxury fashion brands. In order to expand business partnership, Luxura needed to decide which brand to prioritize as their main brand partnership based on historical performance.
Backround Luxura is an e-commerce company that exclusively sells high-end fashion brands including Adibi, Balena, and Celinna . These brands have seen increasing market share over the past 3 years and rely on Luxura as their sole retail partner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luxura Analysis Part 2</title>
      <link>https://hansproject.github.io/projects/luxura-analysis2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hansproject.github.io/projects/luxura-analysis2/</guid>
      <description>Situation This is the continuation of Luxura Analysis Part 1. In this project, we continue our analysis on an individual customer&amp;rsquo;s purchase data to provide personalized insights.
Backround Luxura is an e-commerce platform selling high-end fashion brands. Mr. Chu is one of their top customers and investors who heavily purchases from his favorite brand on Luxura, Adibi.
However, Mr. Chu wants to better manage his expenses going forward. He has spent a significant portion of his luxury budget on Adibi items.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>theLook eCommerce 2022 - SQL</title>
      <link>https://hansproject.github.io/projects/thelook-ecommerce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hansproject.github.io/projects/thelook-ecommerce/</guid>
      <description>Situation I conducted SQL analysis on ecommerce data from TheLook to provide growth and retention insights to inform optimization decisions during a potential crisis.
Backround TheLook is an ecommerce clothing retailer anticipating an economic downturn in 2023. To optimize their business, management needs to strategically cut costs in underperforming areas.
TheLook lacks insights into their category growth and customer retention metrics. This data is required to determine which categories have momentum versus which are stagnating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IBM HR Analytics</title>
      <link>https://hansproject.github.io/projects/ibm-hr-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hansproject.github.io/projects/ibm-hr-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Situation This project was conducted during my role as a Data Analyst student at RevoU. In this project, we use IBM as organization that experiencing a high annual attrition rate of 15% , leading to many vacant positions.
DISCLAIMER: This project is focused on exploring the basic concepts of business case understanding. The data cleaning, EDA, and GBM modelling processes are not shown directly in the slide deck. You can access google colab to see how it works (at the end).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoFood Customer Journey Analysis</title>
      <link>https://hansproject.github.io/projects/gofood-customer-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hansproject.github.io/projects/gofood-customer-journey/</guid>
      <description>Situation I was hired as a Data Analyst at Gojek, a ride-hailing and delivery company. I collaborated with product and business teams to define metrics and analyze customer journeys for GoFood , Gojek&amp;rsquo;s food delivery service.
Backround Gojek is a super app providing ride-hailing, food delivery, and digital payment services in Southeast Asia. GoFood, their food delivery business, has grown rapidly but faces fierce competition.
While Gojek tracks high-level business metrics, they lacked visibility into detailed customer journeys and events .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
